# **Pete Nguyen**

petehnguyen@outlook.com | (202) 909-6602 | www.linkedin.com/in/petehnguyen | Active Secret Clearance

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Army veteran with 6 years of service and experience managing teams, programs, and students as a Radiology Department supervisor at a community teaching hospital. Established reputation as an effective team member and leader driven to set and meet both team and organizational goals. Passionate about technical solutions and facilitates want to help provide solutions to modern problems. Eager learner and a determined individual ready to showcase proactiveness and willingness to set and attack goals.

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Certified Scrum Master (CSM) Scrum Alliance, 2022
- Microsoft Technology Associate: Software Development Fundamentals (MTA 98-36), 2021

## **SKILLS**

- Technical: OOP | C# | SQL | AZURE | HTML | CSS | ASP.NET MVC | petehnguyen (github.com)
- Soft Skills: Bilingual Vietnamese | Accountability | Detail Oriented | Resiliency

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Microsoft Software and Systems Academy Cloud Application Developer Student

January 2022 - Present

- Selected for a highly competitive program that supports transitioning service members as they gain the knowledge necessary to enter the technology industry, as well as mentors that guide them through fundamental professional development skills and concepts.
- Instructed in Cloud Application Development, learned to design, write, build, and support applications and programs.
- Gained fundamental skills in C#, SQL, CSS, HTML, and Object-Oriented Programming.
- Learned conceptual frameworks for Web Application Development, ASP.NET MVC, and Azure Application Development.
- Gained foundational knowledge on executing full life-cycle software development and code development.
- Built, modified, and ran more than 100 queries against T-SQL databases via SQL Server Management Studio for data analysis and interpretation.

# Martin Army Community Hospital MEDCOM (Army Medical Command) Radiology Department Supervisor

June 2016 - January 2022

- 2021 Regional Health Command-Atlantic Solider of the Year
- 2021 Martin Army Community Hospital Soldier of the Year
- 2021 Martin Community Hospital Best Leader Competition Winner
- Radiology department manager over both soldiers and Department of Defense civilians delivering training on clinical and combat readiness strategies while supporting overall welfare through providing mentorship and productive teamwork.
- Project manager for Radiology supply strategies and negotiated with 50+ vendors to complete projects within scope and under budget.
- Team manager to a team of 15 personnel conducting monthly professional counseling, routine inspections and ensured standards were met in accordance with regulations for bi-annual technical and physical assessments.
- Provided direct radiology support for over 94,000 beneficiaries including US military, multinational forces, and Department of Defense civilians and their families.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Purdue Global University**

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology–Programming and Software Development Associate of Science: Health Sciences

January 2021 - Present November 2019